<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Inspiration - pixetty</title>
	<atom:link href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/category/inspiration/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 07:09:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Fine Art Portrait: 6 Tips to Create Your Own</title>
		<link>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-1/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=post-1</link>
					<comments>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-1/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vignesh@52]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 15:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themes.getmotopress.com/pixetty/?p=40</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Fine art portrait photography is a slightly ambiguous genre. Some argue that in order to be considered fine art, an image&#160;must feature specific elements. Others claim that we, as photographers, can decide whether our work fits into the fine art genre or not. It also has patterns that you can use to create your own [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-1/">Fine Art Portrait: 6 Tips to Create Your Own</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fine art portrait photography is a slightly ambiguous genre. Some argue that in order to be considered fine art, an image&nbsp;must feature specific elements. Others claim that we, as photographers, can decide whether our work fits into the fine art genre or not.</p>



<span id="more-40"></span>



<p>It also has patterns that you can use to create your own fine art. Some of these include poses, expressions, and lighting that will add an elegant touch to your portraits.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">1. Use Classic Backgrounds to Highlight the Subject</h4>



<p>More often than not, fine art portraits have very simple backgrounds that put the spotlight on the subjects. Having a very simple background will highlight every feature on your subject’s face, like skin textures, clothes, and the objects they’re holding.</p>



<p>Many fine art portraits have black backgrounds. This creates the illusion of depth and compels the eye to focus exclusively on the model.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="850" height="480" src="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/post-content.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-18" srcset="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/post-content.jpg 850w, https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/post-content-300x169.jpg 300w, https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/post-content-768x434.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">2. Use Inanimate Objects</h4>



<p>Editing is definitely optional. If you want to keep your photos as raw as possible, you can still create very stunning fine art portraits. If you’re in the mood to experiment, though, you’re in for a treat!</p>



<p>These items either told a story about their subjects or served as eye-catching decorations. We can learn a thing or two from these masters by using inanimate objects in our photographs.Things like books, flowers, and instruments all have textures that could turn your photos into true fine art portraits. As you look for objects, keep your model’s story in mind.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">3. Be Creative With Makeup and Costumes</h4>



<p>Fine art photography is nothing without its costumes and makeup. Some photographers like to take the traditional route and dress their models using costumes that look like they belong to royalty. Many focus on both makeup and clothes.</p>



<p>You can use anything. I often use thrift store finds in my portraits. They’re unusual, affordable, and vibrant enough for fine art portraits. Be as creative as you want! Use secondhand scarves, hats, dresses, or even gloves. Pretend that you’re preparing for a film role. It sounds silly, but your imagination can take you to the most exciting places if you allow it to.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">4. Don’t Be Afraid of Motion Blur</h4>



<p>In general, motion blur is something many portrait photographers tend to avoid for understandable reasons. Details are something you don’t want to take for granted. However, you should occasionally blur parts of your photo during your shoot or post-production.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>The results will show you the importance of getting out of your comfort zone and experimenting with unpredictable techniques.</p></blockquote>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">5. Go Faceless</h4>



<p>As important as facial expressions are, they don’t have to be featured in a portrait. Sometimes, a simple photo of a hand, a strand of hair, or a curved spine can evoke memories far more powerful than a photo of a stranger’s face. There’s something comforting, even relatable, about seeing a human figure and not just an unfamiliar face.</p>



<p>Faceless fine art portraits are ideal for self-portraits, experimental photos, or test shots with subjects who don’t want to show their faces. Taking them will open up a whole new world for you. You’ll have nothing but movements, body parts, and backdrops to focus on.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">6. Give Yourself an Editing Challenge</h4>



<p>Editing is definitely optional. If you want to keep your photos as raw as possible, you can still create very stunning fine art portraits. If you’re in the mood to experiment, though, you’re in for a treat!</p>



<p>What you may not notice immediately is how much love he pours into his editing work; his portraits are carefully color corrected to look the way they do. Without his editing skills, he wouldn’t have a powerful signature style.Editing is definitely optional. If you want to keep your photos as raw as possible, you can still create very stunning fine art portraits. If you’re in the mood to experiment, though, you’re in for a treat!</p><p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-1/">Fine Art Portrait: 6 Tips to Create Your Own</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tips for creating better portraits</title>
		<link>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-2/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=post-2</link>
					<comments>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vignesh@52]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 13:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themes.getmotopress.com/pixetty/?p=38</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Creating a compelling portrait can take a lot of thought and design. But here are three practical tips you can use to improve your image. Choose the right lens Choosing the correct lens can make a huge impact on your portraits. Traditional portrait lenses are 85 mm, 100 mm, and 135 mm, but I much [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-2/">Tips for creating better portraits</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Creating a compelling portrait can take a lot of thought and design. But here are three practical tips you can use to improve your image.</p>



<span id="more-38"></span>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-choose-the-right-lens">Choose the right lens</h4>



<p>Choosing the correct lens can make a huge impact on your portraits. Traditional portrait lenses are 85 mm, 100 mm, and 135 mm, but I much prefer the focal range offered by a 24-70mm zoom. At its widest setting of 24 mm, it allows you to capture a lot of environment around your subject. Select a longer focal length if you are closer to your subject. Zoom to 70 mm for an intimate portrait.</p>



<p>A 24-70mm lens is one of the most versatile lenses for portrait photography as it covers the range from wide to moderate telephoto. On the left is the 24-70 mm lens at 24 mm, and on the right is 24-70 mm lens at 70 mm</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-know-your-lens-for-better-portraits">Know your lens for better portraits</h4>



<p>Different focal lengths flatten perspective to various degrees. Understanding the feeling that this creates is another tool in creating memorable portraits. Filling the frame results in different looks — and feeling — depending on focal length. Shooting a tight portrait with a slightly wide-angle lens results in rounder facial features than you get when shooting with a longer focal length.</p>



<p>Note the difference in perspective and background between similarly cropped portraits shot with a wide-angle 35 mm lens on the left, and a telephoto 135 mm lens on the right — Both shots 1/200 sec. at f/2.0.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-zoom-with-your-feet">Zoom with your feet</h4>



<p>Never forget that the best zoom lens you’ll ever own are those things at the bottom of your legs called “feet.” Don’t forget to shoot both tight and loose even when shooting with a prime lens.</p><p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-2/">Tips for creating better portraits</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Create A Diptych in Food Photography</title>
		<link>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-4/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=post-4</link>
					<comments>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-4/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vignesh@52]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 13:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themes.getmotopress.com/pixetty/?p=32</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Diptychs in food photography are a great way to showcase a food story. It’s something that I often think about when creating new work, even though I don’t always showcase my images using this composition method. The great thing about Diptychs is that you can use new or old work, even ongoing work to create [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-4/">How To Create A Diptych in Food Photography</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Diptychs in food photography are a great way to showcase a food story. It’s something that I often think about when creating new work, even though I don’t always showcase my images using this composition method.</p>



<span id="more-32"></span>



<p>The great thing about Diptychs is that you can use new or old work, even ongoing work to create a story.</p>



<p>In this post we’re going to look at:</p>



<ul><li>What is a diptych and why we use it in photography.</li><li>How it helps us tell a food story.</li><li>3 steps to creating a beautiful diptych.</li><li>Examples of how I have used diptychs.</li><li>Ideas you can use for your diptychs.</li></ul>



<p>Ready to create a Diptych? Let’s get into it.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">What is a Diptych?</h4>



<p>Pronounced like <em>‘dip-tik’</em>, a diptych is a presentation of two images together that combined, tell a story. The images could be from the same shoot, or show similar subjects or present contrasting elements.</p>



<p>You could even present images from different shoots that when combined tell more of a story or show a theme than if they were on their own.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">It’s All About The Story You Want to Tell.</h4>



<p>The biggest consideration when creating a diptych is deciding what story you want to tell with your images.</p>



<p>Before you start, what is the message you want to viewer to receive? What do you want them to feel or discover? The answers to these questions will help you to craft and concept the two images.</p>



<p>If both of the images come from the same shoot, you’ll want to think about how to present the images differently. Some ideas of what you can do that are:</p>



<ul><li>Using different focal lengths to capture your subjcect.</li><li>Shooting different angles.</li><li>Cooked vs uncooked food.</li><li>Wide vs narrow captures.</li><li>Different types of lighting.</li></ul><p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-4/">How To Create A Diptych in Food Photography</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Write A Photographer Bio for Your Website</title>
		<link>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-5/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=post-5</link>
					<comments>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-5/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vignesh@52]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 13:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themes.getmotopress.com/pixetty/?p=30</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Writing about yourself can be difficult. It’s not easy to identify your defining characteristics and sum yourself up in a neat and concise manner. And this is true when you’re writing a photographer bio for your website. The bio page is an important part of your website. It’s something that potential clients will look at [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-5/">How to Write A Photographer Bio for Your Website</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Writing about yourself can be difficult. It’s not easy to identify your defining characteristics and sum yourself up in a neat and concise manner. And this is true when you’re writing a photographer bio for your website.</p>



<p>The bio page is an important part of your website. It’s something that potential clients will look at to get an idea about the person behind the pictures. In this post, we’ll help you write an awesome photographer bio for your professional website. We have tips, suggestions, and the dos and don’ts for the perfect bio.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Do You Need A Bio Page on Your Website?</h4>



<p>The short answer is yes. As a photographer, you may think your portfolio&nbsp;speaks for itself. The logic may be to let the photos do the talking. The bulk of your website will be dedicated to your photography work, but the bio page also plays a crucial role on your website.</p>



<p>Your portfolio is your shop window. It shows what you have to offer as a photographer. But a good bio introduces the viewer to the shopkeeper behind the glass. It adds heart and depth, showing that you’re more than just a storefront. It shows you’re a fully formed professional photographer.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">How to Write a Photographer Bio</h4>



<p>Now we’ll get into the nuts and bolts of writing a photographer bio for your website. We’ll give you some valuable suggestions, along with some of the dos and don’ts.</p>



<p>Of course, you should avoid typos and grammatical errors. But we’ll take a look at the finer points for writing an excellent photographer bio.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Introduce Yourself</h4>



<p>The first sentence is critical when writing a bio. It introduces you as a professional and sets the tone for what’s to come. The reader will know if they want to continue after just a few words.</p>



<p>Use the first sentences to introduce yourself. Tell the reader your name and what you do. You can also add some extra details, like your location. But don’t get carried away.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Let Your Personality Shine in Your Bio</h4>



<p>Many photographers keep their bios formal and very matter-of-fact. Other’s like to use humour to make their bio more memorable. You can go either way, as long as you’re portraying yourself naturally.</p>



<p>This is your photographer bio. It should reflect your personality as a person and as a photographer. The words need to connect you to the rest of your website without misrepresenting yourself to employers.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Don’t Focus On Size</h4>



<p>When it comes to website bios, bigger isn’t always better. The word count of your bio will depend on several factors. You don’t need to focus on hitting a thousand words. You need to make sure the content is valid.</p>



<p>One factor that will influence the length of your bio is style. If you don’t enjoy writing, keeping it short will suit your personality. If you have a narrative style of photography, maybe your bio will take on a narrative style as well.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Stay Relevant</h4>



<p>Whether your bio is short or long, the main thing is to stay relevant. Fill your paragraphs with valuable information about yourself and your photography work.</p>



<p>A potential client won’t stick around long if you don’t hold their attention. They don’t want to read your life story. And they don’t need to know about your favourite colour or which Spice Girl you had a crush on in 1997.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Use Your Professional Language</h4>



<p>When I say “use your professional language”, I don’t mean cutting out the swear words and profanities. Of course, you should avoid these. But I mean you should write your bio with the language you usually use.</p>



<p>If you speak to clients in English, you should write the bio in that language. If you’re bilingual, you can have two copies of the text, one in each language.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Include a Photo</h4>



<p>In writing a bio, you’re creating a written portrait of yourself. But including a photograph of yourself can add a human touch. Unless you’re a self-portrait artist, you might not appear in your own gallery, so it’s nice to put a face to a name.</p>



<p>The photograph you choose should fit the style of your work. You can have a portrait in your own style if you’re a portrait photographer. If you’re a nature or wildlife photographer, you can have a shot of yourself in action.</p><p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-5/">How to Write A Photographer Bio for Your Website</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Determine Your Dominant Eye for Better Photography</title>
		<link>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-6/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=post-6</link>
					<comments>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-6/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vignesh@52]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 13:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themes.getmotopress.com/pixetty/?p=28</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that one of your eyes is more dominant than the other? This article will show how using your dominant eye can help you create better compositions and improve your photography! What is a Dominant Eye? Humans are blessed with a trait called ocular dominance. It means one of our eyes is stronger than [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-6/">How to Determine Your Dominant Eye for Better Photography</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that one of your eyes is more dominant than the other? This article will show how using your dominant eye can help you create better compositions and improve your photography!</p>



<span id="more-28"></span>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">What is a Dominant Eye?</h4>



<p>Humans are blessed with a trait called ocular dominance. It means one of our eyes is stronger than the other. And that stronger eye provides a slightly greater degree of input to the visual part of your brain. In the same way that we’re right-hand dominant or left-hand dominant, we’re either right-eye dominant or left-eye dominant.</p>



<p>With that said, it is possible to have a mixed (alternating) ocular dominance. In that case, your eyes take turns being dominant.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">How Eye Dominance Works</h4>



<p>The part of our brain that processes visual information (the visual cortex) has strips of neurons (nerve cells) called dominant eye columns. These bands of neurons respond preferentially to input from one eye or the other. It depends on the information. This is important for our binocular vision.</p>



<p>But ‘plasticity’ in these dominant eye columns suggests this eye dominance&nbsp;can be variable. Some people find that their eye dominance alternates or is challenging to determine.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">How to Figure Out Your Dominant Eye</h4>



<p>When looking at an object, you use both eyes. You use both your dominant eye and your non-dominant eye. Your eyes don’t create an image by mixing together two views of the same object. You see an object with your dominant eye, and the other eye acts as support.</p>



<p>There are simple ways to figure out your dominant eye. Follow this simple eye test to find out which one of your eyes is dominant.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Eye Dominance Test</h4>



<p>Remember, eye dominance and handedness (your dominant hand) are not directly related. But they are significantly associated.</p>



<p>Follow these steps to determine your dominant eye:</p>



<ol><li>Extend your arms out in front&nbsp;of you.</li><li>Face your palms out.</li><li>Bring your hands together to form a triangular with your fingers and thumbs.</li><li>Look through this hole at a fixed object, like a picture on a wall.</li><li>First, look at the object using both eyes.</li><li>Then close your left eye. Does the object in the triangle&nbsp;move? If it does, your right eye is dominant.</li><li>Double-check. Look at the object again with both eyes</li><li>Close your right eye.&nbsp;Does the object in the triangle&nbsp;move? If it does, your left eye is dominant.</li></ol>



<p>If the triangle moves an equal distance with both eyes, you may have mixed eye dominance.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why Using Your Dominant Eye is Useful</h4>



<p>Knowing and using your dominant eye is beneficial for many activities. It is especially helpful when determining the precise positions of things… like accurately shooting targets like in archery.</p>



<p>And, of course, this translates into taking photos. Using your dominant eye to look through your camera’s viewfinder allows you to&nbsp;compose better images. Your dominant eye will give you a more precise preview of the shot you are taking.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Benefits of Using Your Non-Dominant Eye</h4>



<p>I tried shooting first with my dominant eye (right) and then with my non-dominant eye (left). At first, I found no difference. I shoot with my dominant eye automatically because I’m right-handed. But then I wanted to use my peripheral vision—to keep an eye out while looking through the viewfinder with my dominant eye. I found it impossible to do this with my non-dominant eye.</p>



<p>You can try it yourself. Keep both eyes open and alternate between both eyes. You might find that your dominant eye repeats the exact image you see, making it very difficult to see peripherally.</p><p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-6/">How to Determine Your Dominant Eye for Better Photography</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Negative Space in Photography: The Essential Guide</title>
		<link>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-7/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=post-7</link>
					<comments>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-7/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vignesh@52]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 13:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themes.getmotopress.com/pixetty/?p=26</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The term negative space may sound problematic, but it’s actually an essential component of almost every great image. In fact, if you want to create gorgeous photos, you must master negative space; that way, you can take shots that feature balanced, harmonious, eye-catching arrangements. (You can also capture wonderfully minimalistic compositions, as I discuss down [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-7/">Negative Space in Photography: The Essential Guide</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The term negative space may sound problematic, but it’s actually an essential component of almost every great image. In fact, if you want to create gorgeous photos, you must master negative space; that way, you can take shots that feature balanced, harmonious, eye-catching arrangements. (You can also capture wonderfully minimalistic compositions, as I discuss down below.)</p>



<span id="more-26"></span>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">What is negative space?</h4>



<p>Negative space refers to areas of a composition that are empty, bland, or otherwise uninteresting. That’s why negative space is also called white space; it’s where nothing is really happening.</p>



<p>In photography, negative space is often made up of certain elements:</p>



<ul><li>Water</li><li>Sky</li><li>Walls</li><li>Sand</li></ul>



<p>Note that all of these elements tend to fade easily into the background, and that’s why they make such great negative space. An empty sky does not draw the eye, any more than a blank white wall, a stretch of empty sand, and so on.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Positive space versus negative space</h4>



<p>Positive space is the complete opposite of negative space. Negative space rejects the eye, while positive space steals the spotlight. You see, positive space is the area of a photo that includes elements of interest, the area that includes the main subject, the area where the viewer’s eye goes first.</p>



<p>In the photo below, there is plenty of positive space, but very little negative space. The flag, the buildings, and the trees all act as positive space. Even the clouds provide some positive space, thanks to their interesting arrangement and texture. The biggest patch of negative space is the sky, which takes up a tiny portion of the shot.</p>



<p>Now, positive space can be anything, but here are some common examples:</p>



<ul><li>Faces</li><li>People</li><li>Buildings</li><li>Birds</li><li>Wildlife</li><li>Mountains</li></ul>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">Let the scene dictate your negative space and positive space combination</h5>



<p>Every scene has a different ratio of negative space to positive space.</p>



<p>And while you, as the photographer, can zoom in, change perspective, and crop to emphasize certain parts of the scene, you need to be flexible; you need to be able to embrace a scene that’s full of negative space, just the same as you embrace a scene filled with positive space.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Use negative space to balance out positive space</h4>



<p>A key goal of photographic composition is to achieve visual balance. You want your images to feel whole, complete, satisfying.</p>



<p>And one way to achieve balance is by identifying your positive space, then countering it with negative space.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Experiment with minimalism</h4>



<p>Minimalistic compositions use negative space to great effect. In fact, they’re all about negative space; they take lots of negative space, include a touch of positive space, and create an eye-catching result.</p>



<p>Here’s an example of a minimalist image, where the shadow acts as positive space, while the bricks provide some empty negative space:</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Use negative space to convey emotion</h4>



<p>Negative space tends to be bleak, even melancholy, especially in black and white images.</p>



<p>Use this fact. Tell a story with your composition – a story that’s laced with sadness, or loneliness, or quiet pleasure.</p>



<p>Of course, you should let the scene guide you, as I emphasized above. But you can also carefully add more negative space to your composition by zooming out, or by finding a uniquely empty background, etc.</p><p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-7/">Negative Space in Photography: The Essential Guide</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-7/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Emotional Photography: 5 Tips to Add Feeling to Your Photos</title>
		<link>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-8/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=post-8</link>
					<comments>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-8/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vignesh@52]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 12:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themes.getmotopress.com/pixetty/?p=24</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The best photography often conveys emotions, but how do you create emotional photography? How do you add feelings to your photos so you can move the viewer and ensure they connect with the piece? I’ve spent years honing my ability to infuse photos with emotions. And in this article, I’ll share my absolute favorite techniques [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-8/">Emotional Photography: 5 Tips to Add Feeling to Your Photos</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The best photography often conveys emotions, but how do you create emotional photography? How do you add feelings to your photos so you can move the viewer and ensure they connect with the piece?</p>



<span id="more-24"></span>



<p>I’ve spent years honing my ability to infuse photos with emotions. And in this article, I’ll share my absolute favorite techniques – so that you can capture powerful, moving images, too!</p>



<p>Of course, not all viewers experience the same emotions in response to the same photos, so don’t feel pressure to convey specific feelings to everyone. Instead, use these tips, plus your personal emotions, to create powerful, one-of-a-kind images.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Identify your mood before shooting</h4>



<p>The emotional state of the photographer – that’s you! – has the largest impact on the emotional quality of your photos. So whenever you head out with your camera, before you take a single shot, or even look for a shot, ask yourself: How am I feeling today? Then let that emotion guide your shooting, and channel it into your photos.</p>



<p>After all, it’s tough to infuse an image with an emotion that you aren’t feeling. If you’re over the moon with happiness, you’ll struggle to find sad or bleak compositions. And if you’re down in the dumps, creating awe-inspiring or uplifting images won’t be easy. So start by identifying your emotions. Look for compositions that align with those feelings.</p>



<p>At the same time, it’s often worth rechecking your feelings periodically throughout your photoshoot. Depending on the view, the light, chance encounters, etc., emotions can change, and you don’t want to miss out on emotionally resonant shots because you’re searching for the wrong thing.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Simplify the shot (try using a telephoto lens)</h4>



<p>In wide, busy, expansive scenes, emotions often get lost. Yes, the emotion might be there, but the viewer will have a hard time noticing – the image may fall a bit flat, at least from an emotional point of view.</p>



<p>So if you’re looking to create emotional photography, consider simplifying the shot. Exclude elements from your frame. Choose a perspective that highlights a single area of interest, not the entire scene.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Focus on faces</h4>



<p>Faces are full of emotion. The eyes are the windows to the soul, after all, and often show anger, joy, sadness, love, and so much more.</p>



<p>Plus, faces can convey emotions through puffy eyes, tears, wrinkles, etc. So if you want feelings to really shine through, train your lens on people’s faces!</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Set your camera down and observe</h4>



<p>When I tell people to stop shooting and put the camera away, I often get criticized, yet it’s an important part of photography – especially photography infused with feelings.</p>



<p>Setting down your camera gives you time to observe the world. Just look around and see what pulls at your consciousness. Ask yourself: What interests me? What draws me? What do I want to capture? What matters to me about this scene?</p>



<p>These questions only take a minute or two, but they’ll help you identify new, emotionally resonant compositions, plus they might clarify your ideas about a scene and show you the way forward.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Return to the same scenes repeatedly</h4>



<p>Scenes look different on different days, and your feelings are different on different days, too. Take advantage of that fact.</p>



<p>If you’re shooting a subject that you can return to, then do it. The street or beach or room or person will have a different feel on different days, especially if you’re photographing outdoors and the weather changes often.</p><p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-8/">Emotional Photography: 5 Tips to Add Feeling to Your Photos</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-8/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>High Speed Sync in 4 Easy Steps</title>
		<link>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-9/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=post-9</link>
					<comments>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-9/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vignesh@52]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 12:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themes.getmotopress.com/pixetty/?p=22</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Strobes and Speedlights are fantastic tools to add to your photography arsenal. Understanding how to use their high-speed sync feature is important. You may have heard of high-speed sync flash, but what exactly is it for? In the four points below, you will learn exactly what high-speed sync flash means. You will also learn how [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-9/">High Speed Sync in 4 Easy Steps</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Strobes and Speedlights are fantastic tools to add to your photography arsenal. Understanding how to use their high-speed sync feature is important. You may have heard of high-speed sync flash, but what exactly is it for?</p>



<span id="more-22"></span>



<p>In the four points below, you will learn exactly what high-speed sync flash means. You will also learn how it works, plus how and when to use it. We will also take a look at some of the best products on the market today that enable you to use this feature.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">What Is High-Speed Sync?</h4>



<p>High-speed sync (HSS) allows you to sync the light from a flash when using a shutter speed faster than your camera’s native sync.</p>



<p>We know that most DSLRs have a native sync speed of 1/250th of a second. Anything faster is beyond the camera’s ability to sync with flash. It will likely cause unwanted effects. Using a higher shutter speed than your camera’s native sync can result in over-exposed images. These sometimes produce black bars across the image. These are created by the flash only partly illuminating the sensor.</p>



<p>These areas are where the camera’s shutter curtains stop the flash. This prevents the flash from exposing the digital sensor. You could use a neutral density filter but still will not have full control over your settings. A better alternative is to use HSS.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">How Does High-Speed Sync Flash Work?</h4>



<p>Shooting anything above 1/250th is unmanageable with normal Speedlight or strobe flash. But why?</p>



<p>With faster shutter speeds, there is no opportunity for the flash to expose onto the sensor. This is because of how close each shutter curtain is to the other and the short flash duration. The single burst from the flash will then only expose onto a small part of the sensor.</p>



<p>High-speed sync forces the flash to fire many bursts of light throughout exposure time. When it does so, it creates an even distribution of light across the sensor.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">When Do You Use High-Speed Sync?</h4>



<p>There are many different situations to consider high speed sync in tricky lighting conditions.</p>



<p>In conditions where your aperture (f-stop) has priority, using HSS will give you greater control over your scene. It allows the use of a wider aperture without over-exposing the image. This is often the case with bright scenes with a soft focus on your subject. It can also be for when you need a shallow depth of field in the background.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">How to Use High-Speed Sync</h4>



<p>If you are taking wide-aperture portraits outside in ambient light, you will likely need to compensate with a high shutter speed. Taking your shot at f 4 or lower in bright sunlight can result in unflattering shadows on your subject’s face. It can also blow out the highlights in your background. Using flash is a great way to resolve these issues.</p>



<p>So how can we control our scene using HSS to balance foreground, background, and ambient light for an even exposure? You first need a flash lighting system that supports HSS.</p><p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-9/">High Speed Sync in 4 Easy Steps</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-9/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cool Geometric Photography Ideas</title>
		<link>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-10/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=post-10</link>
					<comments>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-10/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vignesh@52]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 12:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themes.getmotopress.com/pixetty/?p=20</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Geometric photography is the art of finding and harnessing the world’s geometry through imagery. We use our cameras to turn our geometrical surroundings into powerful and dynamic images. Lead With Lines Once you start looking, you’ll find lines everywhere. Bold, thin, wavy, or sharp—there are countless types of lines. And you can use them to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-10/">Cool Geometric Photography Ideas</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Geometric photography is the art of finding and harnessing the world’s geometry through imagery. We use our cameras to turn our geometrical surroundings into powerful and dynamic images.</p>



<span id="more-20"></span>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Lead With Lines</h4>



<p>Once you start looking, you’ll find lines everywhere. Bold, thin, wavy, or sharp—there are countless types of lines. And you can use them to strengthen your composition in geometric photography.</p>



<p>The geometry of lines helps us visualize our surroundings. They define space, momentum, and emphasis. Lines delineate both conceptual and physical designs. They provide a scaffold for ideas and experiences.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Repeat Yourself</h4>



<p>Repetition involves repeating a subject many times for greater impact within an image. You can find geometric shapes that repeat to create patterns throughout your images. With each repetition, the geometry in the image is emphasized. It gives your geometric photography rhythm and structure. The shapes become part of the narrative of your photograph.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Suggest Symmetry</h4>



<p>Symmetry is the visual balance of one or more subjects within a composition. It occurs both naturally and artificially. It is often tied to the geometric properties of a photograph. Symmetry visually and psychologically pleasing to encounter. And it adds an even flow to a photograph.</p>



<p>An image doesn’t need to be perfect to achieve the impression of symmetry. You can find symmetry by using reflections in glass or water. Or you can look for similar geometric shapes in your compositions.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Use Color</h4>



<p>Color can liven up a geometric image, snagging the viewer’s eye. But color also can work on a deeper, more psychological level. Colors are linked to emotional experiences. Different colors hold specific meanings for different people. While red shows passion, blue denotes calmness. You introduce a new layer of experience to geometric photography by incorporating color.</p>



<p>Bringing color theory into your work adds depth and meaning to your geometric photography. You can use different color patterns to give your images a more substantial emotional feel as Turkish photographer Yener Torun displays in the image below.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Try Black and White</h4>



<p>Black and white can’t rely on color to get attention. It depends on shape and form. The contrast of black and white helps create dynamic shapes and lines.</p>



<p>You don’t have blocks of color. But you can find strong shapes made from black and white. And you can also look for contrasting shades of grey.</p>



<p>Black and white photography is about finding light and dark areas. Look for the regions where light meets dark. The light beams and shadows create a world of shape that surrounds you.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Go Textural</h4>



<p>Texture defines the way an image feels. It allows the viewer to connect with a photograph on a physical level. Rough, smooth, wrinkly, or slippery—most subjects are made from textural qualities.</p>



<p>Geometric subjects operate on many textural levels. Polished metallic surfaces give an impression of smoothness and modernity. Weather-worn geometric architecture can feel rough and old. You can almost feel the rough texture of old bricks.</p><p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-10/">Cool Geometric Photography Ideas</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-10/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Product Photography: 5 Tips for Stunning Shots</title>
		<link>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-11/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=post-11</link>
					<comments>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-11/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vignesh@52]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 12:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themes.getmotopress.com/pixetty/?p=9</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Getting great product photos often seems daunting, but it’s simpler than you might think. As an experienced product photographer, I’ve spent years learning the ins and outs of the craft. And in this article, I aim to share it all. 1. Get your camera on a tripod For one, they protect against blur. Once you [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-11/">Product Photography: 5 Tips for Stunning Shots</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Getting great product photos often seems daunting, but it’s simpler than you might think. As an experienced product photographer, I’ve spent years learning the ins and outs of the craft. And in this article, I aim to share it all.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">1. Get your camera on a tripod</h4>



<p>For one, they protect against blur. Once you mount your camera (or smartphone) on a tripod, then you can lengthen your shutter speed as much as you like without risking camera shake.</p>



<p>So what tripod should you buy? There are a huge variety of tripods available, all with different features and at different price points. As long as the tripod is strong enough to support your gear, you’ll probably be just fine – though if you can afford it, consider grabbing a tripod that can bend your camera over at ninety degrees. That way, you can easily capture popular flat-lay shots for Instagram.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">2. Use the right lighting for the product</h4>



<p>Yes, there are certain product photographers who spend hours or even days lighting a single setup and getting it perfect. And there are product photographers who work in a studio with a handful of strobes and dozens of modifiers. But while there is a time and a place for slow, complex product photography, it’s not necessary for all product photos, and you can certainly capture great product shots without such difficult lighting arrangements.</p>



<p>In fact, you can do product photography with only natural window light; simply put the product on the table (or even the floor) near a window, make sure it’s angled correctly, and start shooting. (Many people successfully photograph products on a table pulled up to a bright window!)</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">3. Shoot the product from multiple angles</h4>



<p>Product photography is about helping the customer understand exactly what they’re getting. And when people are buying online, they can’t pick the product up, nor can they touch it.</p>



<p>So it’s your job, as the photographer, to convey all the small details to a potential purchaser. The best way to do that? Make sure you capture a variety of product angles. Shoot from above. Shoot from the left and the right. Make sure you emphasize every portion of the product, including all the little details.</p>



<p>Close-up shots are especially important if the item is handmade. By getting in close, you can convey the care and consideration the artisan put into their work. These little details are what differentiates handmade products from their mass-manufactured counterparts – so be sure to show them off!</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">4. Find out how the images will be displayed</h4>



<p>Different product images are used in different ways. For instance, a client might want to use your photos for social media – or they might plan to use your photos on an e-commerce website. Plus, different vendors will have different specifications for how photographs look best on their sites. Some might prefer 3:2 landscape images, while others will work only with square-format files.</p>



<p>And then you should tailor your product photos to their specifications. For instance, if you are shooting for someone with an Etsy store, they might want photos that look great on their product page (generally portrait-orientation shots) and that work well as search thumbnails (these are landscape oriented). So you should carefully capture images that look good when cropped to both portrait and landscape orientations. (You may want to leave plenty of white space around the product, which you can then delete in post-processing.)</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">5. Don’t forget the packaging</h4>



<p>A huge percentage of product sales happen online, so the packing of a product contributes heavily to the first impression of a brand. As a result, artisan companies and small businesses often spend lots of time considering their packaging and branding – which means that you’ll have a beautiful, complementary prop to include in your shots.</p>



<p>You can capture plenty of photos featuring both the product and the box. Try shooting the product in the box, the product on top of the box, and the product next to the box. And if the packaging is interesting enough, shoot it on its own.</p><p>The post <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-11/">Product Photography: 5 Tips for Stunning Shots</a> first appeared on <a href="https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty">pixetty</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://vigneshkannan52.github.io/pixetty/2022/03/27/post-11/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
